Hi, everyone, and welcome back to introduction to deep learning,
嗨，大家好，欢迎回到深度学习导论，
we had a really awesome kickoff day yesterday,
昨天我们有一个非常棒的开讲日，
so we're looking to keep that same momentum all throughout the week
所以我们希望在整个星期保持同样的势头，
and starting with today
从今天开始，
and today, we're really excited to be talking about
今天，我们很高兴能够讨论，
actually one of my favorite topics in this course,
也是在这门课上我最喜欢的话题之一，
which is how we can build computers that can achieve the sense of sight and vision.
那就是我们如何制造能够实现视觉的计算机。
Now, I believe that sight
现在，我相信视觉，
and specifically, like I said, vision is one of the most important human senses that we all have,
具体地说，就像我说的，视觉是我们所有人最重要的人类感官之一，
in fact sighted people rely on vision quite a lot
事实上，有视力的人很大程度上依赖于视觉，
in our day to day lives,
在我们的日常生活中，
from everything from walking around, navigating the world,
从四处走动，环游世界，
interacting and sensing other emotions in our colleagues and peers.
到与同事和同龄人互动和感知其他情感，
And today we're going to learn about how we can use deep learning and machine learning
今天，我们将学习如何使用深度学习和机器学习
to build powerful vision systems,
来构建强大的视觉系统，
that can both see and predict what is where
这些系统可以看到和预测什么是什么，
by only looking at raw visual inputs.
只需查看原始的视觉输入，
And I like to think of that phrase
我喜欢把这句话看作是
as a very concise and sweet definition of what it really means to achieve vision.
对实现视觉真正意味着什么的一个非常简洁和甜蜜的定义。
But at its core, vision is actually so much more than just understanding what is where,
但在其核心，视觉实际上远远不止是理解什么是在哪里，
it also goes much deeper,
它也更深入，
takes this scene, for example,
比如这个场景，
we can build computer vision systems
我们可以建立计算机视觉系统，
that can identify, of course, all of the objects in this environment,
当然，它可以识别这个环境中的所有对象，
starting first with the yellow taxi or the Van parked on the side of the road,
首先从黄色的出租车或停在路边的货车开始，
but we also need to understand each of these objects at a much deeper level,
但我们也需要在更深的层面上了解这些物体，
not just where they are,
不仅是它们在哪里，
but actually predicting the future, predicting what may happen in the scene next,
而且是预测未来，预测下一步可能发生的事情，
for example, that the yellow taxi is more likely to be moving and dynamic into the future,
例如，黄色出租车未来更有可能移动和动态，
because it's in the middle of the lane,
因为它位于车道中央，
compared to the white Van which is parked on the side of the road,
而不是停在路边的白色面包车，
even though you're just looking at a single image,
即使你只看着一张图片，
your brain can infer all of these very subtle cues
你的大脑也可以推断出所有这些非常微妙的线索，
and it goes all the way to the pedestrians on the road
它一直延伸到道路上的行人，
and even these even more subtle cues in the traffic lights and the rest of the scene as well,
甚至红绿灯和场景中其他地方的更微妙的线索，
now accounting for all of these details in the scene is an extraordinary challenge,
现在，在场景中解释所有这些细节是一个非同寻常的挑战，
but we as humans do this so seamlessly within a split second,
但作为人类，我们在一瞬间就做到了这一点，
I probably put that frame up on the slide
可能我把这个幻灯片的图片放上来，
and all of you within a split second could reason about many of those subtle details
你们所以人一瞬间就可以推理出很多微秒的细节，
without me even pointing them out,
在没有我指出的情况下，
but the question of today's class is,
但今天课堂上的问题是，
how we can build machine learning and deep learning algorithms,
我们如何构建机器学习和深度学习算法，
that can achieve that same type and subtle understanding of our world.
可以实现对我们世界的同样类型和微妙的理解。
And deep learning in particular is really leading this revolution of computer vision
尤其是深度学习真正引领了这场计算机视觉革命，
and achieving site of computers,
并实现了计算机的现场定位，
for example, allowing robots to pick up on these key visual cues in their environment,
例如，使机器人能够在其环境中捕捉到这些关键的视觉线索，
critical for really navigating the world together with us as humans,
这对于真正与我们人类一起导航世界至关重要，
these algorithms that you're going to learn about today have become so mainstreamed,
你今天将要学习的这些算法已经变得如此主流，
in fact, that they're fitting on all of your smartphones,
事实上，它们适用于你所有的智能手机，
in your pockets,
放在你的口袋里，
processing every single image that you take,
处理你拍摄的每一张图像，
enhancing those images, detecting faces and so on and so forth.
增强这些图像，检测人脸，等等。
And we're seeing some exciting advances ranging,
我们看到了一些令人兴奋的进步，
all the way from biology and medicine,
从生物学和医学，
which we'll talk about a bit later today,
我们将在今天晚些时候讨论，
to autonomous driving and accessibility as well.
到自动驾驶和可访问性。
And like I said,
正如我所说的，
deep learning has taken this field as a whole by storm in over the past decade or so,
深度学习在过去十年左右的时间里像风暴一样席卷了整个领域，
because of its ability critically like we were talking about yesterday,
因为它的能力就像我们昨天讨论的那样，
its ability to learn directly from raw data and those raw image inputs in what it sees in its environment
它能够直接从原始数据和原始图像输入中学习它在环境中看到的东西，
and learn explicitly how to perform,
并明确地学习如何执行，
like we talked about yesterday,
就像我们昨天谈到的，
what is called feature extraction of those images in the environment,
环境中那些图像的特征提取，
and one example of that is through facial detection and recognition,
其中一个例子是通过面部检测和识别，
which all of you are going to get practice with in today's and tomorrow's labs
你们所有人都将在今天和明天的实验中练习，
as part of the grand final competition of this class.
作为这门课总决赛的一部分。
Another really go to example of computer vision is
计算机视觉的另一个真正的例子是
in autonomous driving and self driving vehicles,
在自动驾驶和自动驾驶车辆中，
where we can take an image as input
我们可以将一幅图像作为输入，
or maybe potentially a video as input, multiple images
或者可能将视频作为输入，多幅图像，
and process all of that data,
并处理所有这些数据，
so that we can train a car to learn
这样我们就可以训练汽车学习，
how to steer the wheel or command a throttle or actuate a braking command,
如何驾驶方向盘或控制油门或执行制动命令，
this entire control system,
这个整个控制系统，
the steering, the throttle, the braking of a car can be executed end to end,
汽车的转向、油门和刹车可以端到端地执行，
by taking as input the images and the sensing modalities of the vehicle
方法是将车辆的图像和传感模式作为输入，
and learning how to predict those actuation commands,
并学习如何预测这些驱动命令，
now, actually this end to end approach,
实际上，这种端到端的方法，
having a single neural network do all of this
让一个神经网络来做所有这些事情，
is actually radically different than the vast majority of autonomous vehicle companies,
与绝大多数自动驾驶汽车公司完全不同，
like if you look at Waymo for example, that's a radically different approach,
例如，如果你看一下 Waymo ，那是一种截然不同的方法，
but we'll talk about those approaches in today's class
但我们将在今天的课上讨论这些方法，
and in fact this is one of our vehicles that we've been building at MIT
事实上，这是我们在 MIT 建造的一辆车，
in my lab and cell just a few floors above this room
在我的实验室里，就在这个房间上方几层，
and we'll again share some of the details on this incredible work.
再次，我们将分享这项令人难以置信的工作的一些细节。
But of course, it doesn't stop here with autonomous driving,
当然，它并不止步于自动驾驶，
these algorithms directly the same algorithms that you'll learn about in today's class
这些你们将在今天的课程中直接学习的相同算法，
can be extended all the way to impact healthcare, medical decision making
可以一直扩展到影响医疗保健、医疗决策，
and finally even in these accessibility applications,
最终甚至在这些无障碍应用程序中，
where we're seeing computer vision algorithms helping the visually impaired,
我们看到计算机视觉算法帮助视障人士，
so for example in this project,
举个例子，在这个项目中，
researchers have built deep learning enabled devices, that could detect trails,
研究人员已经建立了深度学习设备，可以检测步道，
so that visually impaired runners could be provided audible feedback,
这样视力受损的跑步者就可以得到声音反馈，
so that they too could, you know, navigate when they go out for runs.
这样他们也可以在外出跑步时导航。
And like I said,
就像我说的，
we often take many of these tasks that we're going to talk about in today's lecture for granted,
我们经常把今天课程中将要讨论的许多任务视为理所当然的，
because we do them so seamlessly in our day to day lives,
因为我们在日常生活中无缝地完成了这些任务，
but the question of today's class is going to be,
但今天这门课的问题是，
at its core,
在它的核心，
how we can build a computer to do these same types of incredible things,
我们如何制造一台计算机来做这些不可思议的事情，
that all of us take for granted day to day.
我们每天都认为理所当然的。
And specifically, we'll start with this question of,
具体地说，我们将从这个问题开始，
how does a computer really see,
计算机到底是如何看东西的，
and even more detailed than that is,
更详细的是，
how does a computer process an image,
计算机是如何处理图像的，
if we think of,
如果我们认为，
you know, site as coming to computers through images,
[网站]是通过图像进入计算机的，
then how can a computer even start to process those images.
那么计算机如何开始处理这些图像。
Well, to a computer, images are just numbers, right,
对计算机来说，图像只是数字，
and suppose, for example, we have a picture here of Abraham Lincoln,
例如，假设我们这里有一张 Abraham Lincoln 的照片，
okay, this picture is made up of what are called pixels,
好的，这张图片是由所谓的像素组成的，
every pixel is just a dot in this image,
每个像素在这张图像中只是一个点，
and since this is a gray scale image,
因为这是一个灰度图像，
each of these pixels is just a single number,
所以每个像素都只是一个数字，
now we can represent our image now as this two dimensional matrix of numbers,
现在我们可以将我们的图像表示为这个二维数字矩阵，
and because, like I said, this is a gray scale image,
因为，就像我说的，这是一幅灰度图像，
every pixel is corresponding to just one number at that matrix location,
每个像素只对应于该矩阵位置上的一个数字，
now assume, for example, we didn't have a gray scale image,
现在假设，例如，我们没有灰度图像，
we had a color image that would be an RGB image,
我们有一个彩色图像，它将是 RGB 图像，
so now every pixel is going to be composed not just of one number, but of three numbers,
所以现在每个像素将不只由一个数字组成，而是由三个数字组成，
so you can think of that as kind of a 3D matrix instead of a 2D matrix,
所以你可以把它想象成三维矩阵，而不是二维矩阵，
where you almost have three two dimensional matrix that are stacked on top of each other.
你有三个二维矩阵堆叠在一起。
So now with this basis of basically numerical representations of images,
所以现在有了这个基本的图像数字表示的基础，
we can start to think about,
我们可以开始考虑，
how we can or what types of computer vision algorithms we can build,
我们如何或者我们可以建立什么类型的计算机视觉算法，
that can take these systems as input and what they can perform.
来将这些系统作为输入，以及它们可以执行什么操作。
So the first thing that I want to talk to you about is,
所以我想跟你们谈的第一件事是，
what kind of tasks do we even want to train these systems to complete with images,
我们到底想要训练这些系统来完成什么样的图像任务，
and broadly speaking there are two broad categories of tasks,
大体上讲，有两大类任务，
we touched on this a little bit in yesterday's lecture,
我们在昨天的课程中稍微谈到了这一点，
but just to be a bit more concrete in today's lecture,
但为了在今天的课程中更具体一些，
those two tasks are either classification or regression,
这两项任务要么是分类，要么是回归，
now in regression, your prediction value is going to take a continuous value, right,
对于回归，你的预测值会有一个连续的值，
that could be any real number on the number line,
这可以是数轴上的任何实数，
but in classification, your prediction could take one of, let's say, k or n different classes,
但在分类中，你的预测可能是 k 或 n 个不同的类别之一，
these are discrete different classes.
这些是离散的不同类别。
So let's consider first the task of image classification,
所以，让我们首先考虑图像分类的任务，
in this task we want to predict an individual label for every single image
在这个任务中，我们想要为每个单独的图像预测一个单独的标签，
and this label that we predict is going to be one of n different possible labels that could be considered,
我们预测的这个标签将是可以考虑的 n 个不同的可能标签之一，
so for example, let's say we have a bunch of images of US preidents
例如，假设我们有一系列美国总统的图像，
and we want to build a classification pipeline
我们想要建立一个分类管道，
to tell us which president is in this particular image that you see on the screen,
来告诉我们在屏幕上看到的这张图像中是哪位总统，
the goal of our model in this case is going to be basically to output a probability score,
在这种情况下，我们模型的目标基本上是输出一个概率分数，
probability of this image containing one of these different preidents,
这个图像包含这些不同总统之一的概率，
and the maximum score is going to be ultimately the one
最大的分数最终将是
that we infer to be the correct preident in the image.
我们推断为图像中正确的总统的那个。
So in order to correctly perform this task and correctly classify these images,
所以，为了正确地执行这项任务，并正确地对这些图像进行分类，
our pipeline, our computer vision model needs the ability to be able to tell us
我们的计算机视觉模型需要能够告诉我们
what is unique about this particular image of Abraham Lincoln, for example,
这张特定的例如 Abraham Lincoln 图像的独特之处，
versus a different picture of George Washington versus a different picture of Obama for example.
与 George Washington 的不同图像和 Obama 的不同图像。
Now another way to think about this whole problem of image classification or image processing
现在，考虑图像分类或图像处理的整个问题的另一种方式，
at its high level is in terms of features,
从高层次上是，从特征的角度，
or think of these as almost patterns in your data or characteristics of a particular class,
或者将这些视为你的数据的模式或特定类别的特征，
and classification then is simply done
分类可以简单的完成，
by detecting all of these different patterns in your data
通过检测数据中所有这些不同的模式，
and identifying when certain patterns occur over other patterns,
并识别某些模式何时出现在其他模式上，
so for example, if the features of a particular class are present in an image,
例如，如果某个特定类别的特征出现在图像中，
then you might infer that that image is of that class,
那么你可能会推断该图像属于该类别，
so for example, if you want to detect cars,
例如，如果你想要检测汽车，
you might look for patterns in your data, like wheels, license plates or headlights,
你可能会在你的数据中查找车轮、车牌或前灯等数据模式，
and if those things are present in your image,
如果这些东西出现在你的图像中，
then you can say with fairly high confidence that,
那么你可以相当自信地说，
your image of a car versus one of these other categories.
你的图像是一辆汽车，而不是这些其他类别。
So if we're building a computer vision pipeline,
所以，如果我们构建一条计算机视觉管道，
we have two main steps really to consider,
我们有两个主要步骤需要考虑，
The first step is that we need to know what features or what patterns we're looking for in our data,
第一步是我们需要知道我们在数据中寻找什么特征或模式，
and the second step is we need to then detect those patterns,
第二步是我们需要检测这些模式，
once we detect them,
一旦我们检测到它们，
we can then infer which class we're in.
我们就可以推断我们所在的类别。
Now, one way to solve this is to leverage knowledge about our particular field, right,
现在，解决这个问题的一种方法是利用我们特定领域的知识，
so if we know something about our field,
所以，如果我们对我们的领域有所了解，
for example about human faces,
例如关于人脸的知识，
we can use that knowledge to define our features,
我们可以用这些知识来定义我们的特征，
what makes up a face,
什么构成了一张脸，
we know faces are made up of eyes, noses and ears, for example,
我们知道脸是由眼睛、鼻子和耳朵组成的，
we can define what each of those components look like,
我们可以定义每个组件的外观，
in defining our features,
在定义我们的特征时，
but there's a big problem with this approach,
但这种方法有一个很大的问题，
and remember that images are just these three dimensional arrays of numbers,
记得图像就是这些数字的三维数组，
they can have a lot of variation even within the same type of object,
即使在同一类型的物体中，它们也可能有很大的变化，
these variations can include really anything,
这些变化可以包括任何东西，
ranging from occlusions to variations in lighting, rotations, translations into a class variation.
从遮挡到照明，旋转、平移，在类别变动中。
And the problem here is,
这里的问题是，
that our classification pipeline needs the ability to handle
我们的分类流水线需要处理
and be invariant to all of these different types of variations,
所有这些不同类型的变化并保持不变的能力，
while still being sensitive to all of the inter class variations,
同时仍然对所有种类间变化敏感，
the variations that occur between different classes.
不同种类之间发生的变化。
Now, even though our pipeline could use features that we as humans,
尽管我们的管道可以使用我们作为人类的特征，
you know, define manually define based on some of our prior knowledge,
基于我们的一些先验知识，手动定义的特征，
the problem really breaks down,
问题被分解为，
in that these features, become very non robust,
这些特征变得非常不健壮，
when considering all of these vast amounts of different variations that images take in the real world.
当考虑到图像在现实世界中的大量不同变化时。
So in practice, like I said,
所以在实践中，就像我说的，
your algorithms need to be able to withstand all of those different types of variations,
你的算法需要能够承受所有这些不同类型的变化，
and then the natural question is that,
然后自然的问题是，
how can we build a computer vision algorithm to do that
我们如何建立一个计算机视觉算法来做到这一点，
and still maintain that level of robustness,
并仍然保持这种水平的健壮性，
and what we want is a way to extract features
我们想要的是一种提取特征的方法，
that can both detect those features, those patterns in the data,
既能检测数据中的那些特征，那些模式，
and do so in a hierarchical fashion,
又能以分层的方式做到这一点，
so going all the way from the ground up, from the pixel level to something with semantic meaning,
从头开始，从像素级别到具有语义意义的东西，
like for example, the eyes or the noses in the human face.
例如，人脸的眼睛或鼻子。
Now, we learned in the last class,
我们在上一节课中学到了，
that we can use neural networks exactly for this type of problem,
我们可以使用神经网络来解决这类问题，
neural networks are capable of learning features directly from data,
神经网络能够直接从数据中学习特征，
and learn, most importantly, a hierarchical set of features,
而且，最重要的是，学习一组分层的功能，
building on top of previous features that it's learned
在之前的功能基础上构建，
to build more and more complex set of features.
构建越来越复杂的功能集。
Now, we're going to see exactly how neural networks can do this in the image domain,
现在，我们将确切地了解神经网络如何在图像领域做到这一点，
as part of this lecture,
作为这节课的一部分，
but specifically neural networks will allow us
具体地说，神经网络将允许我们，
to learn these visual features from visual data,
从视觉数据中学习这些视觉特征，
if we construct them cleverly,
如果我们巧妙地构建这些视觉特征，
and the key point here is that,
这里的关键点是，
actually the models and the architectures that we learned about in yesterday's lecture,
我们在昨天的课程中了解到的模型和体系结构，
and so far in this course,
到目前为止，
we'll see how they're actually not suitable or extensible to today's, you know, problem domain of images
我们将看到它们如何不适合或扩展到今天的图像问题域，
and how we can build and construct neural networks a bit more cleverly to overcome those issues.
以及我们如何更巧妙地构建和构造神经网络来克服这些问题。
So maybe let's start by revisiting what we talked about in lecture one,
让我们先回顾一下我们在第一课中谈到的内容，
which was where we learned about fully connected networks,
也就是我们学习的全连接网络，
now these were networks that, you know, have multiple hidden layers
这些网络有多个隐藏层，
and each neuron in a given hidden layer is connected to every neuron in its prior layer,
在给定的隐藏层中的每个神经元都连接到它的前一层中的每个神经元，
so it receives all of the previous layers inputs as a function of these fully connected layers,
所以，它接收作为这些完全连接的层的函数的所有先前层的输入，
now let's say that we want to directly, without any modifications, use a fully connected network,
现在，让我们假设我们想要直接使用完全连接的网络，而不做任何修改，
like we learned about in lecture one,
就像我们在第一课中了解到的那样，
with an image processing pipeline,
使用图像处理管道，
so directly taking an image and feeding it to a fully connected network,
直接使用图像并将其提供给完全连接网络，
could we do something like that.
我们能做些类似的事情吗。
Actually in this case, we could,
事实上，在这种情况下，我们可以，
the way we would have to do it is,
我们要做的是，
remember that because our image is a two dimensional array,
记住，因为我们的图像是一个二维数组，
the first thing that we would have to do is collapse that to a one dimensional sequence of numbers,
我们必须做的第一件事是将它折叠成一个一维数字序列，
because a fully connected network is not taking in a two dimensional array,
因为一个完全连接网络不是接受一个二维数组，
it's taking in a one dimensional sequence.
而是接受一个一维序列。
So the first thing that we have to do is,
所以，我们必须做的第一件事是，
flatten that two dimensional array to a vector of pixel values
将二维数组展平为像素值的向量，
and feed that to our network,
并将其提供给我们的网络，
in this case, every neuron in our first layer is connected to all neurons in that input layer, right,
在这种情况下，我们第一层中的每个神经元都连接到输入层中的所有神经元，
so in that original image flattened down,
所以，在原始图像展平后，
we feed all of those pixels to the first layer,
我们将所有这些像素提供给第一层，
and here you should already appreciate the very important notion,
在这里，你应该已经意识到一个非常重要的概念，
that every single piece of spatial information that really defined our image
那就是真正定义我们图像的每一条空间信息，
that makes an image an image is totally lost already,
使图像成为图像的信息都已经完全消失了，
before we've even started this problem,
在我们开始这个问题之前，
because we've flattened that two dimensional image into a one dimensional array,
因为我们已经将二维图像展平为一维数组，
we've completely destroyed all notion of spatial information.
所以我们已经完全摧毁了空间信息的所有概念。
And in addition, we really have an enormous number of parameters,
此外，我们确实有大量的参数，
because this system is fully connected,
因为这个系统是完全连接的，
take for example, in a very, very small image,
举个例子，在一个非常非常小的图像中，
which is even 100 by 100 pixels,
它甚至是 100 乘以 100 像素，
that's an incredibly small image in today's standards,
在今天的标准下，这是一个令人难以置信的小图像，
but that's going to take 10000 neurons just in the first layer,
但这将需要在第一层中的 10000 个神经元，
which will be connected to, let's say 10000 neurons in the second layer,
它将连接到，比如第二层中的 10000 个神经元，
the number of parameters that you have just in that one layer alone is going to be 10,000 squared parameters,
仅在这一层中的参数数量就将是 10000 个平方参数，
it's going to be highly inefficient,
这将是非常低效的，
you can imagine if you want to scale this network to
你可以想象，如果您想要将此网络扩展到
even a reasonably sized image that we have to deal with today,
我们今天必须处理的合理大小的图像，
so not feasible in practice,
所以在实践中是不可行的，
but instead we need to ask ourselves,
相反，我们需要问问自己，
how we can build and maintain some of that spatial structure,
我们如何才能建立和维护一些非常独特的空间结构，
that's very unique about images here into our input
这种空间结构在我们的输入中，
and here into our model most importantly.
以及最重要的是，在我们的模型中。
So to do this, let's represent our two 2D as its original form,
要做到这一点，让我们将二维图像表示为其原始形式，
as a two dimensional array of numbers,
即一个二维数组，
one way that we can use spatial structure here inherent to our input is
我们可以使用空间结构连接我们的输入的一种方式是，
to connect what are called basically these patches of our input to neurons in the hidden layer,
将我们输入的这些部分连接到隐藏层中的神经元，
so for example, let's say that each neuron in the hidden layer, that you can see here
例如，假设这里你可以看到的隐藏层中的每个神经元，
only is going to see or respond
它们将只看到或做出反应，
to a certain set or a certain patch of neurons in the previous layer, right,
对于上一层中的一组或某一块神经元，
so you could also think of this as almost a receptive field
所以你也可以认为这是一个感受野，
or what the single neuron in your next layer can attend to in the previous layer,
或者你下一层中的单个神经元在上一层中所能关注的，
is not the entire image,
不是整个图像，
but rather a small receptive field from your previous image,
而是你上一张图像中的一个小的感受野，
now notice here how the region of the input layer,
现在注意输入层的区域，
which you can see on the left hand side here,
你可以在左侧看到，
influences that single neuron on the right hand side
如何影响右侧的单个神经元，
and that's just one neuron in the next layer,
这只是下一层中的一个神经元，
but of course you can imagine basically defining these connections across the whole input, right,
当然，你可以想象在整个输入中定义这些连接，
each time you have the single patch on your input,
每一次，你的输入上都有块，
that corresponds to a single neuron output on the other layer,
对应于另一层上的单一神经元，
and we can apply the same principle
我们可以应用相同的原理，
of connecting these patches across the entire image to single neurons in the subsequent layer,
将整个图像中的这些块连接到后续层中的单个神经元。
and we do this by essentially sliding that patch,
我们可以通过滑动块来做到这一点，
pixel by pixel across the input image
在输入图像上逐个像素，
and we'll be responding with, you know, another image on our output layer.
我们将在输出层上使用另一幅图像进行响应。
In this way, we essentially preserve all of that very key and rich spatial information inherent to our input,
通过这种方式，我们基本上保留了我们输入所固有的所有非常关键和丰富的空间信息，
but remember that the ultimate task here is,
但请记住，这里的最终任务是，
not only to just preserve that spatial information,
不仅仅是保存空间信息，
we want to ultimately learn features, learn those patterns,
我们最终想要学习特征，学习这些模式，
so that we can detect and classify these images,
以便我们能够检测和分类这些图像，
and we can do this by waving, waving the connections between the patches of our input,
我们可以通过[挥动]输入块之间的连接来做到这一点，
and, and in order to detect, you know, what those certain features are.
而且，为了检测这些特定的特征是什么。
Let me give a practical example here,
让我在这里举一个实际的例子，
and so in practice, this operation that I'm describing, this patching and sliding operation I'm describing,
所以在实践中，我描述的这个运算，我描述的这个块和滑动运算，
is actually a mathematical operation formerly known as convolution,
实际上是一个数据运算，以前被称为卷积，
we first think about this as a high level,
我们首先认为这是一个高水平，
supposing that we have what's called a four by four pixel patch,
假设我们有一个 4x4 像素的块，
so you can see this four by four pixel patch,
所以你可以看到这个 4x4 像素的小块，
represented in red as a red box on the left hand side,
在左手边用红色表示为一个红色的方框，
and let's suppose, for example,
让我们假设，例如，
since we have a four by four patch,
因为我们有一个 4x4 的块，
this is going to consist of sixteen different weights in this layer,
这将由这一层中的 16 个不同的权重组成，
we're going to apply this same four by four,
我们将应用相同的 4x4 ，
let's call this not a patch anymore,
让我们称这不再是一个块，
let's use the terminology filter,
让我们使用术语 filter ，
we'll apply this same four by four filter in the input,
我们将应用相同的 4x4 filter 作为输入，
and use the result of that operation to define the state of the neuron in the next layer,
并使用该操作的结果来定义下一层中神经元的状态，
and now we're going to shift our filter by, let's say, two pixels to the right,
现在我们要将 filter 向右移动两个像素，
and that's going to define the next neuron in the adjacent location in the future layer,
这将定义未来层中相邻位置的下一个神经元，
and we keep doing this
我们继续这样做，
and you can see that on the right hand side,
你可以看到在右手边，
you're sliding over not only the input image,
你不仅滑过了输入图像，
but you're also sliding over the output neurons in the secondary layer,
还滑过了第二层的输出神经元，
and this is how we can start to think about convolution at a very, very high level.
这就是我们如何开始在非常高的水平上考虑卷积。
But you're probably wondering, right,
但你可能想知道，
not just how the convolution operation works,
不只是卷积运算是如何工作的，
but I think the main thing here to really narrow down on is,
我认为这里真正要缩小范围的主要事情是，
how convolution allows us to learn these features, these patterns in the data that we were talking about,
卷积如何让我们了解我们说讨论的数据中的这些特征，这些模式，
because ultimately that's our final goal,
因为这最终是我们的最终目标，
that's our real goal for this class is to extract those patterns.
这才是我们这门课的真正目标，就是提取这些模式。
So let's make this very concrete by walking through maybe a concrete example, right,
所以让我们通过一个具体的例子来让这个问题变得非常具体，
so suppose, for example, we want to build a convolutional algorithm
例如，假设我们想要构建一个卷积算法，
to detect or classify an X in an image,
来检测或者对图像中的 X 进行分类，
this is the letter X in an image,
这是图像中的字母 X ，
and here, for simplicity, let's just say we have only black and white images, right,
这里，为了简单，假设我们只有黑白图像，
so every pixel in this image will be represented by either a zero or one,
所以在这张图像中的每一个像素将用 0 或 1 表示，
for simplicity, there's no gray scale in this image
为了简单，这张图中没有灰度级，
and actually here so we're representing black as -1 and white as 1,
所以我们把黑色表示为 -1 ，白色表示为 1 ，
so to classify, we simply cannot, you know, compare the left hand side to the right hand side, right,
所以要分类，我们不能简单地比较左手边和右手边，
because these are both Xs,
因为这两个都是 X ，
but you can see that,
但是你可以看到，
because the one on the right hand side is slightly rotated to some degree,
因为右手边的那个稍微旋转了一下，
it's not going to directly align with the X on the left hand side,
它不会直接和左边的 X 对齐，
even though it is an X,
尽管它是一个 X ，
we want to detect X in both of these images,
我们希望在这两个图像中都检测到 X ，
so we need to think about how we can detect those features that define an X a bit more cleverly.
所以我们需要考虑如何更巧妙地检测到定义 X 的那些特征。
So let's see how we can use convolutions to do that,
所以让我们看看我们如何使用卷积来做到这一点，
so in this case for example,
例如，在这种情况下，
instead we want our model to compare images of this X piece by piece or patch by patch,
我们不是希望我们的模型逐块地比较这个 X 的图像，
and the important patches that we look for are exactly these features that will define our X,
我们寻找的重要块正是这些将定义我们的 X 的特征，
so if our model can find these rough feature patches roughly in the same position in our input,
所以如果我们的模型能够在输入中找到这些大致相同位置的粗略特征块，
then we can determine or we can infer,
我们可以确定，或者我们可以推断，
that these two images are of the same type or the same letter, right,
这两个图像是相同类型或相同字母，
it can get a lot better than simply measuring the similarity between these two images,
它可以比简单地测量这两张图像之间的相似性好得多，
because we're operating at the patch level,
因为我们是在块级别操作的，
so think of each patch almost like a miniature image, right,
所以把每个块想象成一个微缩的图像，
a small two dimensional array of values
一个小的二维值数组，
and we can use filters to pick up on when these small patches or small images occur,
我们可以使用 filter 来捕捉这些小块或小图像何时出现，
so in the case of Xs,
所以在 X 的情况下，
these filters may represent semantic things,
这些 filter 可能代表语义的东西，
for example the diagonal lines or the crossings,
例如对角线或交叉点，
that capture all of the important characteristics of the X,
它们捕捉到了 X 的所有重要特征，
so we'll probably capture these features in the arms and the center of our letter in any image of an X,
所以我们可能会在 X 的任何图像中捕捉到我们字母的臂部和中心的这些特征，
regardless of how that image is, you know, translated or rotated or so on,
无论图像如何平移或旋转等等，
and note that even in these smaller matrices, right,
注意，即使在这些较小的矩阵中，
these are filters of weights, right,
这些是权重的 filter ，
these are also just numerical values of each pixel in these many patches
这些也只是这些块中每个像素的数值，
is simply just a numerical value,
只是一个简单的数值，
there are also images in some effect, right,
在某种效果上也有图像，
and all that's really left in this problem,
而所有这些都是这个问题留下的，
and in this idea that we're discussing
在我们讨论的这个想法中，
is to define that operation,
我们定义了一种操作，
that can take these miniature patches
它可以获取这些微小的块，
and try to pick up, you know, detect,
并尝试提取，检测，
when those patches occur in your image and when they maybe don't occur.
这些块何时出现在图像中，以及何时可能不出现。
And that brings us right back to this notion of convolution,
这就把我们带回了卷积的概念，
so convolution is exactly that operation that will solve that problem,
所以卷积正是可以解决这个问题的运算，
convolution preserves all of that spatial information in our input
卷积保存输入数据的空间信息，
by learning image features in those smaller squares of regions that preserve our input data.
通过学习保存在输入数据中小的方块区域中的图像特征。
So just to give another concrete example to perform this operation,
所以，为了给出另一个具体的例子来执行这个操作，
we need to do an element wise multiplication,
我们需要进行逐个元素的乘法，
between the filter matrix, those miniature patches, as well as the patch of our input image, right,
在 filter 矩阵，那些小块以及输入图像的块之间，
so you have basically think of two patches,
所以你有两个块，
you have the weight matrix patch, the thing that you want to detect, which you can see on the top left hand here,
你有权重矩阵块，你想要检测的东西，你可以在这里的左上角看到，
and you also have the secondary patch, which is the thing that you are looking to compare it against in your input image,
你还有第二个块，这是你希望在输入图像中与之进行比较的东西，
and the question is how,
问题是，
how similar are these two patches that you observe between them,
你在它们之间观察到的这两块有多相似，
so for example, this results in a three by three matrix,
例如，这会产生一个 3x3 的矩阵，
because you're doing an element wise multiplication between two small three by three matrices,
因为你要在两个小的 3x3 矩阵进行逐个元素的乘法，
you're going to be left with another three by three matrix,
你会得到另外一个 3x3 的矩阵，
in this case, all of the matrix,
在这种情况下，所有的矩阵，
all of the elements of this resulting matrix, you can see here are ones,
这个结果矩阵的所有元素都是 1 ，
because in every location in the filter and every location in the image patch we are perfectly matching,
因为在 filter 中的每个位置，在图像块中的每个位置，都是匹配的，
so when we do that element wise multiplication, we get ones everywhere,
所以，当我们做逐个像素乘法时，我们全部得到 1 ，
the last step is that we need to sum up the result of that matrix, that element wise multiplication,
最后一步是我们要累加这个矩阵的结果，逐个像素乘法，
and the result is let's say 9, in this case,
在这种情况下，结果是 9 ，
everything was a one, it's a three by three matrix, so the result is 9.
每个都是 1 ，它是一个 3x3 矩阵，所以结果是 9 。
Now, let's consider one more example, right,
现在，让我们再考虑一个例子，
now we have this image in green,
现在我们有这张绿色的图像，
and we want to detect this filter in yellow,
我们想要检测黄色的 filter ，
suppose we want to compute the convolution of this 5x5 image with this 3x3 filter,
假设我们想用这个 3x3 filter 来计算这个 5x5 图像的卷积，
to do this,
要做到这一点，
we need to cover basically the entirety of our image
我们需要覆盖整个图像，
by sliding over this filter piece by piece
通过逐段滑动这个 filter ，
and comparing the similarity or the convolution of this filter across the entire image,
并比较整个图像中这个 filter 的相似性或卷积，
and we do that, again through the same mechanism,
再次，我们通过同样的机制做到这一点，
at every location,
在每个位置，
we compute an element wise multiplication of that patch with that location on the image,
我们计算那个块和在图片中位置的逐个元素乘法，
add up all of the resulting entries
将所有结果条目相加，
and pass that to our next layer.
并将其传递到下一层。
So let's walk through it,
所以让我们来看一下，
first, let's start off in the upper left hand corner,
首先，让我们从左上角开始，
we place our filter over the upper left hand corner of our image,
我们将 filter 放置在图像的左上角，
we element wise multiply,
我们对元素进行相乘，
we add up all the results
我们将所有结果相加，
and we get 4
我们得到 4 ，
and that four is going to be placed into the next layer,
这个 4 将被放入下一层，
this next layer again is another image,
下一层同样是另一幅图像，
but it's determined as the result of our convolution operation,
但它被确定为我们卷积运算的结果，
we slide over that filter to the next location,
我们滑动那个 filter 到下一个位置，
the next location provides the next value in our image
下一个位置提供了图像中的下一个值，
and we keep repeating this process over and over and over again
我们可以一遍又一遍地重复这个过程，
until we've covered our filter over the entire image,
直到我们的 filter 覆盖了整个图像，
and as a result, we've also completely filled out the result of our output feature map,
我们还完整地填写了输出特征图的结果，
the output feature map is basically what you can think of is
输出特征图就是，你可以认为是，
how closely aligned our filter is to every location in our input image.
我们的 filter 每个元素与输入图像中每个位置的匹配程度有多高。
So now that we've kind of gone through the mechanism that defines this operation of convolution,
现在我们已经了解了定义卷积运算的机制，
let's see how different filters
让我们看看如何使用不同的 filter ，
could be used to detect different types of patterns in our data,
来检测数据中的不同类型的模式，
so for example, let's take this picture of a woman's face
举个例子，让我们来看看这张女性的脸部照片，
and the output of applying three different types of filters to this picture, right,
以及对这张照片应用三种不同滤镜的结果，
so you can see the exact filter,
这样你就可以看到准确的 filter ，
they're all 3x3 filters,
它们都是 3x3 的 filter ，
so the exact filters you can see on the bottom right hand corner of the corresponding face,
所以你可以在相应的右下角看到准确的 filter ，
and by applying these three different filters,
通过应用这三种不同的 filter ，
you can see how we can achieve drastically different results,
你可以看到我们如何实现截然不同的结果，
and simply by changing the weights that are present in these 3x3 matrices,
通过简单地改变这些 3x3 矩阵中权重，
you can see the variability of different types of features that we can detect,
你就可以看到我们可以检测到的不同类型特征的可变性，
so for example, we can design filters that can sharpen an image,
例如，我们可以设计 filter 来锐化图像，
make the edges sharper in the image,
使图像中的边缘更清晰，
we can design filters that will extract edges,
我们可以设计 filter 来提取边缘，
we can do stronger edge detection
我们可以进行更强的边缘检测，
by again modifying the weights in all of those filters.
通过再次修改所有这些 filter 中的权重。
So I hope now that all of you can kind of appreciate the power of,
所以现在我希望你们所有人都能体会到这些力量，
you know, number one is these filtering operations
首先，是这些 filter 操作，
and how we can define them mathematically
以及我们数学地定义它们，
in the form of these smaller patch based operations and matrices,
在这些更小的基于块的运算和矩阵的形式，
that we can then slide over an image,
然后我们可以在图像上滑动，
and these concepts are so powerful,
这些概念是如此强大，
because number one, they preserve the spatial information of our original input,
因为首先，它们保留了我们原始输入的空间信息，
while still performing this feature extraction,
同时仍在执行特征提取，
now you can think of,
现在，你可以想到，
instead of defining those filters, like we said on the previous slide,
不是像我们在上一张幻灯片中所说的那样定义这些 filter ，
what if we tried to learn them,
如果我们尝试学习它们，
and remember again, that those filters are kind of proxies for important patterns in our data,
记住，这些 filter 是我们数据中重要模式的某种代理，
so our neural network could try to learn those elements of those small patch filters
所以我们的神经网络可以尝试学习那些小块 filter 中的元素，
as weights in the neural network
作为神经网络中的权重，
and learning those would essentially equate to
学习这些元素本质上等同于
picking up and learning the patterns that define one class versus another class.
挑选和学习定义一个类别与另一个类别的模式。
And now that we've gotten this operation and this understanding under our belt,
现在我们已经得到了这次行动和理解，
we can take this one step further,
我们可以进一步推进这一步，
we can take this singular convolution operation
我们可以利用这种奇异的卷积运算，
and start to think about how we can build entire layers, convolutional layers, out of this operation,
并开始考虑如何在这种运算的基础上构建完整的层，卷积层，
so that we can start to even imagine convolutional networks and neural networks.
这样我们就可以开始想象卷积网络和神经网络。
And first we'll take a look at, you know, what are called,
首先，我们来看看所谓的，
well, what you ultimately create by creating convolutional layers and convolutional networks is
通过创建卷积层和卷积网络，你最终创建的就是，
what's called a CNN, a convolutional neural network.
所谓的 CNN ，卷积神经网络。
And that's going to be the core architecture of today's class,
这将是今天课程的核心架构，
so let's consider a very simple CNN,
让我们考虑一个非常简单的 CNN ，
that was designed for image classification,
它是为图像分类而设计的，
the task here again is to learn the features directly from the raw data
这里的任务是直接从原始数据中学习特征，
and use these learned features for classification towards some task of object detection that we want to perform.
并使用这些学习的特征对我们想要执行的目标检测任务进行分类。
Now there are three main operations to a CNN
现在 CNN 有三个主要操作，
and we'll go through them step by step here,
我们将在这里一步一步地介绍它们，
but then go deeper into each of them in the remainder of this class.
但在这节课的其余部分，我们会深入到每一个操作。
So the first step is convolutions,
所以第一步是卷积，
which we've already seen a lot of in today's class already,
我们在今天的课上已经看过很多，
convolutions are used to generate these feature maps,
卷积是用来生成这些特征图的，
so they take us input both the previous image
所以它们让我们输入先前的图像，
as well as some filter that they want to detect,
以及它们想要检测的一些 filter ，
and they output a feature map of how this filter is related to the original image.
并输出 filter 与原始图像关系的特征图。
The second step is like yesterday,
第二步像昨天一样，
applying a non-linearity to the result of these feature maps,
对这些特征映射的结果应用非线性函数，
that injects some non-linear activations to our neural networks,
向我们的神经网络注入一些非线性激活，
allows it to deal with non-linear data.
使其能够处理非线性数据。
Third step is pooling,
第三步是池化，
which is essentially a down sampling operation
这本质上是一种向下采样操作，
to allow our images, allow our networks to deal with larger and larger scale images
允许我们的图像，允许我们的网络处理越来越大规模的图像，
by progressively down scaling their size,
通过逐渐缩小其大小，
so that our filters can progressively grow in receptive field.
以便我们的 filter 可以在感受野内逐渐增长。
And finally, feeding all of these resulting features to some neural network
最后，将所有这些结果特征提供给某个神经网络，
to infer the class scores,
以推断种类分数，
now, by the time that we get to this fully connected layer,
当我们到达这个完全连接的层时，
remember that we've already extracted our features
记住我们已经提取了我们的特征，
and essentially you can think of this no longer being a two dimensional image,
你可以认为这不再是一个二维图像，
we can now use the methods that we learned about in lecture one
我们现在可以使用我们在第一课中学到的方法，
to directly take those learned features that the neural network has detected
直接获取神经网络检测到的学习特征，
and infer based on those learned features
并根据这些学习特征，
and based on if they were detected or if they were not,
根据它们是否被检测到，
what class we're in.
我们所在的种类。
So now let's basically just go through each of these operations one by one in a bit more detail
现在让我们更详细地逐一介绍这些操作，
and see how we could even build up this very basic architecture of a CNN.
看看我们如何才能建立起 CNN 的这个非常基本的架构。
So first, let's go back and consider one more time the convolution operation,
所以首先，让我们回到过去，再考虑一次卷积运算，
that's central, central core to the CNN,
这是 CNN 的核心，
and as before, each neuron in this hidden layer is going to be
和以前一样，这个隐藏层中的每个神经元都将，
computed as a weighted sum of its inputs,
被计算为其输入的加权和，
applying a bias and activating with a non-linearity,
使用偏置和非线性激活，
should sound very similar to lecture one in yesterday's class,
听起来应该和昨天课程的第一课非常相似，
but except now,
但现在不同的是，
when we're going to do that first step,
当我们要做第一步的时候，
instead of just doing a dot product with our weights,
我们不是只用我们的权重做点积，
we're going to apply a convolution with our weights,
而是用我们的权重进行卷积，
which is simply that element wise multiplication and addition, right,
这就是简单的逐个元素乘法和加法，
and that sliding operation.
还有那个滑动操作。
Now, what's really special here
这里真正特别的是，
and what I really want to stress is the local connectivity,
我真正想强调的是本地连接，
every single neuron in this hidden layer only sees
这一隐藏层中的每一个神经元只能看到
a certain patch of inputs in its previous layer,
其前一层中的某一块输入，
so if I point at just this one neuron in the output layer,
所以，如果我只指向输出层的这一个神经元，
this neuron only sees the inputs at this red square,
这个神经元只能看到这个红色方块的输入，
it doesn't see any of the other inputs in the rest of the image,
它看不到图像其余部分中的任何其他输入，
and that's really important to be able to scale these models to very large scale images,
能够将这些模型缩放到超大规模图像中，这一点非常重要，
now, you can imagine that,
现在你可以想象，
as you go deeper and deeper into your network,
随着你越来越深入你的网络，
eventually, because the next layer you're going to attend to a larger patch,
最终，因为在下一层，你将关注更大的块，
and that will include data from not only this red square,
这将不仅包括这个红色方块的数据，
but effectively a much larger red square that you could imagine there.
而且还包括一个你可以想象到的更大的红色方块。
Now let's define this actual computation that's going on,
现在让我们定义一下进程的实际计算，
for a neuron in a hidden layer,
对于隐藏层中的神经元，
its inputs are those neurons that fell within its patch in the previous layer,
它的输入是那些在上一层落在它的块中的神经元，
we can apply this matrix of weights here, denoted as a 4x4 filter,
我们可以应用这个权重矩阵，表示为 4x4 的 filter ，
that you can see on the left hand side,
你可以在左侧看到，
and in this case we do an element wise multiplication,
在这种情况下，我们进行按元素相乘，
we add the outputs, we apply a bias and we add that non-linearity,
我们累加输出，应用偏置，然后添加非线性，
that's the the core steps that we take in really all of these neural networks,
这是所有神经网络的核心步骤，
that you're learning about in today's and this week's class, to be honest.
我们在今天和本周的课程中学到的。
Now remember that this element wise multiplication and addition operation,
记住这个按元素的乘法和加法运算，
that's sliding operation, that's called convolution
这是滑动运算，这叫做卷积，
and that's the basis of these layers.
这是这些层的基础。
So that defines how neurons in convolutional layers are connected,
所以这定义了卷积层中的神经元是如何连接的，
how they're mathematically formulated,
它们是如何数学表达的，
but within a single convolutional layer,
但在一个卷积层内，
it's also really important to understand,
了解这一点也非常重要，
that a single layer could actually try to detect multiple sets of filters,
单个层实际上可以尝试检测多组 filter ，
maybe you want to detect in one image multiple features, not just one feature,
也许你想在一个图像中检测多个特征，而不只是一个特征，
but you know if you are detecting faces,
但是，如果你在检测人脸，
you don't only want to detect eyes,
你不仅仅想检测眼睛，
you want to detect, you know eyes, noses, mouths, ears,
你想要检测眼睛，鼻子，嘴巴，耳朵，
all of those things are critical patterns that define a face
所有这些都是定义人脸的关键模式，
and can help you classify a face.
可以帮助你对人脸进行分类。
So what we need to think of is actually,
所以我们需要考虑的实际上是，
convolution operations that can output a volume of different images, right,
卷积运算可以输出大量不同的图像，
every slice of this volume effectively denotes a different filter,
这个[体积]的每个切片代表了一个不同的 filter ，
that can be identified in our original input,
可以在我们的原始输入中识别出来，
and each of those filters is going to basically correspond to a specific pattern or feature in our image as well,
每个 filter 也将与我们图像中的特定图案或特征相对应，
think of the connections in these neurons, in terms of, you know, their receptive field once again,
再次想想这些神经元中的连接，它们的感受野，
the locations within the input of that node that they were connected to in the previous layer,
它们在上一层中连接到的该节点的输入内的位置，
these parameters really define,
这些参数真正定义了，
what I like to think of as the spatial arrangement of information,
我喜欢认为的信息的空间排列，
that propagates throughout the network and throughout the convolutional layers in particular.
它在整个网络中传播，特别是在卷积层中传播。
Now, I think just to summarize what we've seen
现在，我想总结一下我们所看到的，
and how connections in these types of neural networks are defined,
以及这些类型的神经网络中的连接是如何定义的，
and let's say how the, how the output of a convolutional network is a volume,
让我们来看看卷积网络的输出是怎样的，
we are well on our way to really understanding, you know, convolutional neural networks and defining them, right,
我们正在朝着真正理解卷积神经网络并定义它们的方向前进，
that's the, what we just covered is really the main component of CNNs,
这就是，我们刚刚谈到的是 CNN 的主要组成部分，
that's the convolutional operation that defines these convolutional layers,
这就是定义这些卷积层的卷积运算，
the remaining steps are very critical as well,
剩下的步骤也非常关键，
but I want to maybe pause for a second
但我想暂停一下，
and make sure that everyone's on the same page with the convolutional operation and the definition of convolutional layers.
确保每个人在卷积运算和卷积层的定义上都是一致的。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Okay, so the next step here is
好的，这里的下一步是，
to take those resulting feature maps that our convolutional layers extract
提取我们的卷积层提取的那些结果特征图，
and apply a non-linearity to the output volume of the convolutional layer,
并将非线性应用于卷积层的输出体积，
so as we discussed in the first lecture,
所以正如我们在第一节课中讨论的，
applying these non-linearities is really critical,
应用这些非线性是非常关键的，
because it allows us to deal with non-linear data
因为它允许我们处理非线性数据，
and because image data in particular is extremely non-linear,
而且因为图像数据特别是高度非线性的，
that's a, you know, a critical component of what makes convolutional neural networks actually operational in practice,
这是卷积神经网络在实践中实际运行的关键组成部分，
in particular, for convolutional neural networks,
特别是，对于卷积神经网络，
the activation function that is really, really common for these models is the ReLU activation function,
对于这些模型来说，非常常见的激活函数是 ReLU 激活函数，
we talked a little bit about this in lecture one and two yesterday,
我们在昨天的第一课和第二课中谈到了这一点，
the ReLU activation function, you can see it on the right hand side,
ReLU 激活函数，你可以在右侧看到它，
think of this function as a pixel by pixel operation,
可以将此函数视为逐个像素的操作，
that replaces basically all negative values with zero,
该操作将所有负值替换为零，
it keeps all positive values the same,
它使所有正值保持不变，
it's the identity function when a value is positive,
当一个值是正值时，它是恒等式函数，
but when it's negative, it basically squashes everything back up to zero,
但当它是负值时，它把一切都压回到零，
think of this almost as a thresholding function, right,
这可以看作是一个阈值函数，
thresholds is everything at zero, anything less than zero comes back up to zero,
阈值是任何等于零，任何小于零的值都会回到零，
so negative values here indicate basically a negative detection in convolution,
所以这里的负值表示卷积中的负检测，
that you may want to just say was no detection, right,
你可能只想说没有检测到，
and you can think of that as kind of an intuitive mechanism for understanding
你可以认为这是一种直观的理解机制，
why the ReLU activation functions is so popular in convolutional neural networks,
为什么 ReLU 激活函数在卷积神经网络中如此受欢迎，
the other, the other popular belief is that ReLU activation functions,
另一种流行的看法是， ReLU 激活函数，
well, it's not a belief,
好的，这不是一种[信仰]，
they are extremely easy to compute and they're very easy and computationally efficient,
它们非常容易计算，而且计算效率很高，
their gradients are very cleanly defined,
它们的渐变被非常清晰地定义，
they're constants except for a piece wise non-nonlinearity,
除了分段非线性外，它们都是常量，
so that makes them very popular for these domains.
这使得它们在这些领域非常受欢迎。
Now the next key operation in a CNN is that of pooling,
现在， CNN 的下一个关键操作是池化，
now pooling is an operation that is at its core,
池化是一项处于其核心的操作，
it serves one purpose
它只有一个目的，
and that is to reduce the dimensionality of the image
那就是逐渐降低图像的维度，
progressively as you go deeper and deeper through your convolutional layers,
随着你在卷积层中越走越深，
now you can really start to reason about this,
现在你可以真正开始思考这一点，
is that when you decrease the dimensionality of your features,
当你降低你的特征的维度时，
you're effectively increasing the dimensionality of your filters, right,
你现在是在增加你的过滤器的维度，
now because every filter that you slide over a smaller image
因为你滑过较小图像的每个 filter
is capturing a larger receptive field that occurred previously in that network,
都捕捉到了以前在该网络中发生的更大的感受野，
so a very common technique for pooling is
所以，一种非常常见的池化技术就是
what's called maximum pooling or max pooling for short,
所谓的最大池化或简称 max 池化，
max pooling is exactly, you know what it sounds like,
max 池化就是，它听起来像什么，
so it basically operates with these small patches again,
所以它基本上是用这些小块来运作的，
that slide over an image,
滑过一张图像，
but instead of doing this convolution operation,
但不是进行卷积运算，
what these patches will do is simply take the maximum of that patch location,
这些块简单地获取块位置的最大值，
so think of this as kind of activating the maximum value that comes from that location,
所以，这可以把这看作是位置的激活的最大值，
and propagating only the maximums,
并且只传播最大值，
I encourage all of you actually to think of maybe brainstorm other ways,
我鼓励大家想一想其他方法，
that we could perform even better pooling operations than max pooling,
让我们可以执行比 max 池化更好的池化操作，
there are many common ways,
有很多常见的方法，
but you could think of some,
但你可以想出一些，
for example, or are mean pooling or average pooling,
例如，或者是算术平均池化或平均池化，
maybe you don't want to just take the maximum,
也许你不想只取最大值，
you could collapse basically the average of all of these pixels into your into a single value in the result,
你可以将所有这些像素的平均值折叠为结果中的单个值，
but these are the key operations of convolutional neural networks at their core,
但这些都是卷积神经网络的核心关键操作，
and now we're ready to really start to put them together
现在我们准备开始将它们组合在一起，
and form and construct CNN all the way from the ground up,
从头到尾形成和构建 CNN ，
and with CNNs, we can layer these operations one after the other,
有了 CNN ，我们可以一个接一个地对这些操作进行分层，
starting first with convolutions non-linearities
首先从卷积非线性开始，
and then pooling and repeating these over and over again
然后池化并反复重复这些操作，
to learn these hierarchies of features,
以了解这些特征的层次结构，
and that's exactly how we obtained pictures like this,
这就是我们如何获得这样的图片，
which we started yesterday's lecture with,
我们昨天的课程一开始就是这样，
and learning these hierarchical decompositions of features
学习这些特征的分层分解，
by progressively stacking and stacking these filters on top of each other,
通过逐步堆叠和堆叠这些 filter ，
each filter could then use all of the previous filters that it had learned.
每个 filter 可以使用它学习到的所有以前的 filter 。
So a CNN built for image classification can be really broken down into two parts,
所以，为图像分类而建立的 CNN 可以分为两个部分，
first is the feature learning pipeline,
首先是特征学习管道，
which we learn the features that we want to detect,
我们学习我们想要检测的特征，
and then the second part is actually detecting those features and doing the classification.
然后第二部分是检测这些特征并进行分类。
Now the convolutional and pooling layers output from the first part of that model,
现在，从模型的第一部分输出的卷积层和池化层，
the goal of those convolutional and pooling layers is
这些卷积和池化层的目标是，
to output the high level features that are extracted from our input,
输出从我们的输入中提取的高级特征，
but the next step is to actually use those features and detect their presence
但下一步是使用这些特征并检测它们的存在，
in order to classify the image.
以便对图像进行分类。
So we can feed these output features into the fully connected layers that we learned about in lecture one,
所以，我们可以将这些输出特征输入到我们在第一课中学到的完全连接层中，
because these are now just a one dimensional array of features
因为这些现在只是一个一维特征数组，
and we can use those to detect, you know, what class we're in,
我们可以使用这些特征来检测我们所在的类别，
and we can do this by using a function called a softmax function,
我们可以使用一个称为 softmax 函数的函数来实现这一点，
you can think of a softmax function as simply a normalizing function,
你可以将 softmax 函数看作是一个简单的正规化函数，
whose output represents that of a categorical probability distribution,
其输出表示绝对概率分布的输出，
so another way to think of this is
所以，另一种考虑方式是，
basically if you have an array of numbers, you want to collapse
如果你有一个数字数组，你想要折叠，
and those numbers could take any real number form,
这些数字可以是任何实数形式，
you want to collapse that into some probability distribution,
你想把它压缩成某种概率分布，
probability distribution has several properties,
概率分布有几个属性，
namely that all of its values have to sum to one,
即它的所有值都必须求和为 1 ，
it always has to be between zero and one as well,
它也必须始终介于 0 和 1 之间，
so maintaining those two properties is what a softmax operation does,
所以，维护这两个属性是 softmax 操作所做的事情，
you can see its equation right here,
你可以在这里看到它的方程式，
it effectively just makes everything positive
它有效地使一切都是正的，
and then it normalizes the result across each other
然后它使结果在彼此之间正规化，
and that maintains those two properties that I just mentioned.
这保持了我刚才提到的两个属性。
Great, so let's put all of this together
好的，让我们把所有这些放在一起，
and actually see how we could program our first convolutional neural network
看看我们如何编写我们的第一个卷积神经网络，
end to end entirely from scratch.
完全从头开始。
So let's start by firstly defining our feature extraction head,
所以，让我们首先定义我们的特征提取头，
which starts with a convolutional layer
它从卷积层开始，
and here 32 filters or 32 features,
这里是 32 个 filter 或 32 个特征，
you can imagine that this first layer, the result of this first layer is to learn,
你可以想象这第一层，这第一层的结果是学习，
not one filter, not one pattern in our image, but 32 patterns,
不是一个 filter ，不是我们图像中的一个模式，而是 32 个模式，
okay, So those 32 results are going to then be passed to a pooling layer
好的，所以这 32 个结果将被传递到池化层，
and then passed on to the next set of convolutional operations,
然后传递到下一组卷积运算，
the next set of convolutional operations now will contain 64 features
下一组卷积运算现在将包含 64 个特征，
will keep progressively growing and expanding our set of patterns that we're identifying in this image,
将逐步增长和扩展我们在这张图像中识别的模式集，
next, we can finally flatten those resulting features that we've identified
接下来，我们最终可以扁平化那些我们已经识别的结果特征，
and feed all of this through our dense layers,
并将所有这些都提供给我们的紧密层，
are fully connected layers that we learned about in lecture one,
也就是我们在第一课中学到的完全相连的层，
these will allow us to predict those final, let's say ten classes,
这将使我们能够预测最终，比如 10 个种类，
if we have ten different final possible classes in our image,
如果我们的图像中有十个不同的最终可能种类，
this layer will account for that
这一层将说明这一点，
and allow us to output using softmax the probability distribution across those ten classes.
并允许我们使用 softmax 输出这十个种类的概率分布。
So, so far we've talked about,
到目前为止，我们已经讨论了，
how we can, let's say use CNNs to perform image classification tasks,
如何使用 CNN 来执行图像分类任务，
but in reality, one thing I really want to stress in today's class, especially towards the end,
但实际上，我在今天的课程中特别想强调的一件事是，
is that this same architecture and same building blocks that we've talked about so far are extensible
我们到目前为止讨论的相同的体系结构和相同的构建块是可扩展的，
and they extend to so many different applications and model types, that we can imagine,
它们可以扩展到我们可以想象的许多不同的应用程序和模型类型，
so for example, when we considered the CNN for classification,
例如，当我们考虑 CNN 进行分类时，
we saw that it really had two parts,
我们看到它实际上有两个部分，
the first part being feature extraction, learning what features to look for,
第一部分是特征提取，学习要寻找什么特征，
and the second part being the classification, the detection of those features.
第二部分是这些特征的分类和检测。
Now, what makes a convolutional neural network really, really powerful is
现在，卷积神经网络真正强大的地方是，
exactly the observation that the feature learning part,
因为观察到特征学习部分，
this first part of the neural network is extremely flexible,
神经网络的第一部分是非常灵活的，
you can take that first part of the neural network,
你可以取走神经网络的第一部分，
chop off what comes after it,
砍掉它后面的部分，
and put a bunch of different heads into the part that comes after,
然后把一堆不同的头放进后面的部分，
the goal of the first part is to extract those features,
第一部分的目标是提取这些特征，
what you do with the features is entirely up to you,
如何处理这些特性完全由你自己决定，
but you can still leverage the flexibility and the power of the first part to learn all of those core features,
但你仍然可以利用第一部分的灵活性和强大功能来学习所有这些核心特性，
so for example, that portion will look for, you know, all of the different image classification domains,
例如，这部分将寻找所有不同的图像分类域，
that future portion after you've extracted the features,
在我们提取特征之后的部分，
or we can also introduce new architectures,
我们也可以引入新体系结构，
that take those features and maybe perform tasks like segmentation or image captioning,
获取这些特征并执行分割或图像说明之类的任务，
like we saw in yesterday's lecture.
像我们在昨天课程中看到的。
So in the case of classification, for example,
例如，在分类的情况下，
just to tie up the, the classification story,
仅将分类故事联系起来，
there's a significant impact in domains like healthcare, medical decision making,
这在医疗保健、医疗决策等领域产生重大影响，
where deep learning models are being applied to the analysis of medical scans
深度学习模型被应用于医学扫描分析，
across a whole host of different medical imagery.
通过一系列不同的医学图像。
Now classification tells us basically a discrete prediction of what our image contains,
现在，分类告诉我们对图像所包含内容的离散预测，
but we can actually go much deeper into this problem as well,
但我们也可以更深入地研究这个问题，
so for example, imagine that we're not trying to only identify that this image is an image of a taxi,
比如，想象一下，我们不仅要识别这张图片是一辆出租车，
which you can see here,
你可以在这里看到，
but also more importantly,
更重要的是，
maybe we want our neural network to tell us not only that this is a taxi,
我们可能希望我们的神经网络不仅能告诉我们这是一辆出租车，
but identify and draw a specific bounding box over this location of the taxi,
还能识别并在出租车的这个位置上画一个特定的边界框，
so this is kind of a two phase problem,
所以这是一个两阶段的问题，
number one is that we need to draw a box
第一，我们需要画一个盒子，
and number two is we need to classify what was in that box,
第二，我们需要对盒子里的东西进行分类，
so it's both a regression problem,
所以这是一个回归问题，
where is the box,
盒子在哪里，
that's a continuous problem as well as a classification problem is what is in that box.
这是一个连续的问题，也是一个在盒子里的分类问题。
Now that's a much, much harder problem than what we've covered so far in the lecture today,
这是一个比我们在今天的课程中所讨论的要困难得多的问题，
because potentially there are many objects in our scene,
因为在我们的场景中可能有很多物体，
not just one object,
而不仅仅是一个物体，
so we have to account for this fact,
所以我们必须解释这样一个事实，
that maybe our could constrain arbitrarily many objects.
也许我们可以约束任意多个对象。
Now our network needs to be flexible to that degree,
现在我们的网络需要灵活到那个程度，
needs to be able to infer a dynamic number of objects in the scene,
需要能够推断场景中对象的动态数量，
and if the scene is only of a taxi,
如果场景只是一辆出租车，
then it should only output, you know, that one bounding box,
那么它应该只输出一个边界框，
but on the other hand, if the image has many objects, potentially even of different classes,
但另一方面，如果图像有许多对象，甚至可能是不同类别的对象，
we need a model that can draw a bounding box for each of these different examples,
我们需要一个模型来为这些不同的示例中的每一个绘制一个边界框，
as well as associate their predicted classification labels to each one independently.
并将它们的预测分类标签独立地与每个示例相关联。
Now this is actually quite complicated in practice,
实际上，这相当复杂，
because those boxes can be anywhere in the image,
因为这些方框可以在图像中的任何位置，
there's no constraints on where the boxes can be
盒子放在哪里没有限制，
and they can also be of different sizes,
它们也可以有不同的大小，
they can be also of different ratios,
它们也可以具有不同的比率，
some can be tall, some can be wide.
有些可能很高，有些可能很宽。
Let's consider a very naive way of doing this first,
首先，让我们考虑一种非常幼稚的方式来做这件事，
let's take our image and start by placing a random box somewhere on that image,
让我们在该图像上的某个位置放置一个随机框，
for example, we just pick a random location, a random size,
例如，我们只需随机选择一个位置，一个随机大小，
we'll place a box right there,
我们就会在那里放置一个盒子，
this box, like I said, has a random location, random size,
这个盒子，就像我说的，有一个随机的位置，随机的大小，
then we can take that box
然后我们可以拿起那个盒子，
and only feed that random box through our convolutional neural network
只把那个随机的盒子送入我们的卷积神经网络，
which is trained to do classification, just classification,
它被训练来进行分类，只是分类，
and this neural network can detect,
这个神经网络可以检测到，
well, number one, is there a class of object in that box or not,
第一，盒子里有没有一类物体，
and if so, what class is it,
如果是的话，是什么种类，
and then what we could do is,
然后我们可以做的是，
we could just keep repeating this process over and over again,
我们可以一遍又一遍地重复这个过程，
for all of these random boxes in our image, you know, many, many instances of random boxes,
对我们图像中的所有这些随机框，很多随机框，
we keep sampling a new box,
我们不断地采样一个新的盒子，
feed it through our convolutional neural network
通过我们的卷积神经网络输入它，
and ask this question what was in the box,
然后问这个问题，盒子里是什么，
if there was something in there, then what is it,
如果里面有什么东西，那是什么，
and we keep moving on until we kind of have exhausted all of the the boxes in the image.
我们继续前进，直到我们用尽了图像中所有的方框。
But the problem here is that,
但这里的问题是，
there are just way too many potential inputs that we would have to deal with,
我们必须处理的潜在输入太多了，
this would be totally impractical to run in a real time system,
这对于在实时系统中运行是完全不切实际的，
for example with today's compute,
例如，用今天的计算机，
it results in way too many scales,
这导致了太多的比例，
especially for the types of resolutions of images that we deal with today.
特别是对于我们今天处理的图像的分辨率类型。
So instead of picking random boxes,
所以，不是选择随机的框，
let's try and use a very simple heuristic, right,
让我们尝试并使用一个非常简单的启发式，
to identify maybe some places with lots of variability in the image,
来识别图像中一些具有很大可变性的位置，
where there is high likelihood of having an objects might be present, right,
其中可能存在对象的可能性很高，
these might have meaningful insights or meaningful objects,
这些可能具有有意义的见解或有意义的对象，
that could be available in our image,
可以在我们的图像中使用，
and we can use those
我们可以利用这些信息，
to basically just feed in those high attention locations to our convolutional neural network,
将那些高关注度的位置输入到我们的卷积神经网络中，
and then we can basically speed up that first part of the pipeline a lot,
然后我们可以大大加快管道的第一部分，
because now we're not just picking random boxes,
因为现在我们不仅仅是挑选随机的盒子，
maybe we use some simple heuristic to identify where interesting parts of the image might be,
也许我们使用一些简单的启发式方法来确定图像的有趣部分可能在哪里，
but still this is actually very slow, in practice,
但这实际上仍然非常慢，在实践中，
we have to feed in each region independently to the model,
我们必须独立地为模型提供每个区域的数据，
and plus it's very brittle,
而且它非常脆弱，
because ultimately the part of the model that is looking at where potential objects might be
因为最终模型中查看潜在对象可能所在位置的部分
is detached from the part that's doing the detection of those objects,
与检测这些对象的部分是分开的，
ideally, we want one model,
理想情况下，我们希望有一个模型，
that is able to both, you know, figure out where to attend to and do that classification afterwards.
既能找出要注意的地方，又能进行分类。
So there have been many variants that have been proposed in this field of object detection,
所以在这个物体检测领域已经提出了很多变种，
but I want to, just for the purpose of today's class,
但我想，为了今天的课程，
introduce you to one of the most popular ones.
向你们介绍最流行的其中之一。
Now, this is a point where this is a model called R-CNN or faster R-CNN,
这是一个被称为 R-CNN 或更快的 R-CNN 的模型，
which actually attempts to learn not only how to classify these boxes,
它试图不仅学习如何对这些盒子进行分类，
but learns how to propose those where those boxes might be in the first place,
而且学习如何提出这些盒子可能在哪里，
so that you could learn how to feed or where to feed into the downstream neural network.
这样你就可以学习如何提供或在哪里提供到下游的神经网络。
Now this means that we can feed in the image to what are called these region proposal networks,
这意味着我们可以将图像输入到所谓的区域提案网络，
the goal of these networks is to propose certain regions in the image that you should attend to,
这些网络的目标是提出图像中你应该注意的某些区域，
and then feed just those regions into the downstream CNNs,
然后将这些区域仅提供给下游 CNN ，
so the goal here is
因此这里的目标是，
to directly try to learn or extract all of those key regions
直接尝试学习或提取所有这些关键区域，
and process them through the later part of the model,
并通过模型的后面部分对其进行处理，
each of these regions are processed with their own independent feature extractors,
这些区域中的每一个都使用它们自己的独立特征提取器来处理，
and then a classifier can be used to aggregate them all
然后，可以使用分类器将它们全部聚集在一起，
and perform feature detection as well as object detection.
并执行特征检测和目标检测。
Now, the beautiful thing about this is that this requires only a single pass through the network,
好的是，它只需要在网络中通过一次，
so it's extraordinarily fast,
所以它非常快，
it can easily run in real time,
可以很容易地实时运行，
and is very commonly used in many industry applications as well,
并且在许多行业应用中也非常常用，
even if it can even run on your smartphone.
它甚至可以在你的智能手机上运行。
So in classification,
所以在分类中，
we just saw how we could predict,
我们只是看到了我们如何预测，
you know, not only a single image, a single object per image,
不仅仅是一张图像，每张图像只有一个物体，
we saw an object detection
我们看到一个物体检测，
potentially inferring multiple objects with bounding boxes in your image,
可能会在你的图像中用边界框推断多个物体，
there's also one more type of task,
还有一种类型的任务，
which I want to point out,
我想指出，
which is called segmentation.
它叫做分割。
Segmentation is the task of classification,
分割是分类的任务，
but now done at every single pixel,
但现在是在每一个单独的像素上做的，
this takes the idea of object detection, which bounding boxes to the extreme,
这使用了目标检测的思想，把方框的边界限制到了极致，
now, instead of drawing boxes,
现在，我们不再画盒子，
we're not even going to consider boxes,
我们甚至不会考虑盒子，
we're going to learn how to classify every single pixel in this image in isolation, right,
我们将学习如何对这张图像中的每一个像素进行分类，
so it's a huge number of classifications that we're going to do
所以我们要做的是大量的分类，
and we'll do this.
我们会这样做。
Well, first let me show this example,
好的，首先让我展示一下这个例子，
so on the left hand side what this looks like,
所以在左手边，这是什么样子，
as you're feeding in an original RGB image,
当你输入原始 RGB 图像时，
the goal of the right hand side is to learn,
右手边的目标是学习，
for every pixel in the left hand side,
对于左手边的每个像素，
what was the class of that pixel, right,
那个像素是什么种类的，
so this is kind of in contrast to just determining, you know, boxes over our image,
所以，这与仅仅确定我们的形象上的框框形成了某种对比，
now we're looking at every pixel in isolation
现在我们孤立地看每一个像素，
and you can see for example,
你可以看到，例如，
you know this pixels of the cow are clearly differentiated from the pixels of the sky or the pixels of the grass, right,
你知道牛的像素与天空或草地的像素明显不同，
and that's a key critical component of semantic segmentation networks,
这是语义分割网络的关键组成部分，
the output here is created by again using these convolutional operations,
这里的输出是通过再次使用这些卷积操作，
followed by pooling operations,
然后是池化操作来创建的，
which learn an encoder which you can think of on the left hand side,
这些操作学习了一个编码器，你可以在左侧想到它，
these are learning the features from our RGB image,
这些是从我们的 RGB 图像中学习特征，
learning how to put them into a space,
学习如何将它们放到一个空间中，
so that it can reconstruct into a new space of semantic labels,
以便它可以重建到一个新的语义标签空间中，
so you can imagine kind of a down scaling
所以你可以想象一种缩小的规模，
and then progress of upsscaling into the semantic space,
然后是进步扩展到语义空间，
but when you do that upscaling,
但当你进行扩展时，
it's important, of course, you can't be pulling down that information,
这一点很重要，当然，你不能抹杀那些信息，
you need to kind of invert all of those operations,
你需要在某种程度上颠倒所有这些操作，
so instead of doing convolutions with pooling,
所以现在不是用池化来做卷积，
you can now do convutions with basically reverse pooling or expansions,
你现在可以用反向的池化或扩展来做卷积，
you can grow your feature sets at every labels.
你可以在每个标签上扩展您的特征集。
And here's an example on the bottom of just a code piece that actually defines these layers,
这是一个代码片段的例子，它定义了这些层，
you can plug these layers, combine them with convolutional layers
你可以插入这些层，将它们与卷积层结合，
and you can build these fully convolutional networks that can accomplish this type of task.
你就可以建立这些完全卷积的网络来完成这种类型的任务。
Now of course, this can be applied in many other applications in health care as well,
当然，这也可以应用于医疗保健中的许多其他应用，
especially for segmenting out, let's say cancerous regions
特别是分割出癌症区域，
or even identifying parts of the blood which are infected with malaria, for example.
甚至识别感染疟疾的血液部分。
And one final example here of self driving cars,
最后一个例子是自动驾驶汽车，
let's say that we want to build a neural network for autonomous navigation,
让我们假设我们想要建立一个用于自动导航的神经网络，
specifically building a model,
特别是建立一个模型，
let's say that can take as input an image
假设它可以接受图像作为输入，
as well as let's say some very coarse maps of where it thinks it is,
以及它认为它所在位置的一些非常粗略的地图，
think of this as basically a screenshot of, you know, the Google maps essentially
把这个想象成一个谷歌地图截图，
to the neural network, right,
给神经网络，
it's the GPS location of the map.
这是地图的 GPS 位置。
And it wants to directly infer not a classification or a semantic classification of the scene,
它不想直接推断场景的分类或语义分类，
but now directly infer the actuation how to drive and steer this car into into the future, right,
而是现在直接推断如何驾驶和驾驶这辆车进入未来，
now this is a full probability distribution over the entire space of control commands, right,
现在，这是整个控制命令空间的全概率分布，
it's a very large continuous probability space,
这是一个非常大的连续概率空间，
and the question is how can we build a neural network to learn this function,
问题是，我们如何建立一个神经网络来学习这种功能，
and the key point that I'm stressing,
我在这里强调的，
with all of these different types of architectures here is,
所有这些不同类型的体系结构的关键点是，
that all of these architectures use the exact same encoder,
所有这些体系结构使用完全相同的编码器，
we haven't changed anything when going from classification to detection to semantic segmentation, and now to here,
从分类到检测再到语义分割，再到这里，我们没有做任何改变，
all of them are using the same underlying building blocks of convolutions, nonlinearities and pooling,
它们都在使用相同的卷积、非线性和池化，
the only difference is that,
唯一的区别是，
after we perform those feature extractions,
在我们执行这些特征提取之后，
how do we take those features and learn our ultimate tasks,
我们如何获取这些特征并学习我们的最终任务，
so for example, in the case of probabilistic control commands,
例如，在概率控制命令的情况下，
we would want to take those learned features
我们想要获取这些学习的特征，
and understand how to predict, you know, the parameters of a full continuous probability distribution,
并了解如何预测全连续概率分布的参数，
like you can see on the right hand side
就像你在右手边看到的，
as well as the deterministic control of our desired destination,
以及我们期望的目的地的确定性控制，
and again like we talked about at the very beginning of this class,
同样，就像我们在这节课一开始谈到的那样，
this model which goes directly from images all the way to steering wheel angles
这个模型直接从图像到方向盘角度，
essentially of the car is a single model,
本质上是汽车的一个模型，
it's learned entirely end to end,
它完全是从头到尾学到的，
we never told the car, for example, what a lane marker is or you know, the rules of the road,
我们从来没有告诉汽车什么是车道标志或者道路规则，
it was able to observe a lot of human driving data,
它能够观察大量的人类驾驶数据，
extract these patterns, these features,
提取这些模式，这些特征，
from what makes a good human driver different from a bad human driver
从优秀的人类司机与糟糕的人类司机的不同之处，
and learn how to imitate those same types of actions that are occurring,
并学习如何模仿发生的相同类型的动作，
so that without any, you know, human intervention or human rules
这样，在没有任何人类干预或人类规则的情况下，
that we impose on these systems,
我们加入这个系统的，
they can simply watch all of this data
他们可以简单地观察所有这些数据，
and learn how to drive entirely from scratch.
完全从零开始学习如何驾驶。
So a human, for example, can actually enter the car,
所以，一个人可以进入汽车，
input a desired destination,
输入想要的目的地，
and this end to end CNN will actually actuate the control commands
这个端到端的 CNN 会启动控制命令，
to bring them to their destination.
将他们带到他们的目的地。
I'll conclude today's lecture,
我将结束今天的演讲，
with just saying that the applications of CNNs,
通过所说的几个 CNN 应用，
we've touched on a few of them today,
我们今天已经谈到了其中的几个，
but the applications of CNNs are enormous,
但是 CNN 的应用是巨大的，
far beyond these examples that I provided today,
远远超出了我今天提供的这些例子，
they all tie back to this core concept of feature extraction and detection
它们都与特征提取和检测这一核心概念联系在一起，
and after you do that feature extraction,
在进行特征提取之后，
you can really crop off the rest of your network
你可以切断网络的其余部分，
and apply it to many different heads
并将其应用于许多不同的头部，
for many different tasks and applications that you might care about,
以执行你可能关心的许多不同的任务和应用，
we've touched on a few today,
我们今天已经谈到了一些，
but there are really so, so many in different domains.
但在不同的领域确实有很多。
And with that I'll conclude
有了这个总结，
and very shortly we'll just be talking about generative modeling,
很快我们就会讨论生成建模，
which is a really central, really central part of today's and this week's lectures series,
这是今天和本周系列讲座的核心，
and after that, later on we'll have the software lab,
在那之后，稍后我们将有一个软件实验，
which I'm excited for all of you to, to start participating in.
我很高兴你们所有人都能开始参与。
And yeah, we can take a short five minute break
是的，我们可以休息五分钟，
and continue the lectures from there.
然后从那里继续讲课。
Thank you.
谢谢。